# MICHAEL PAKULAK

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

## SKILLS

React, JS, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Express.js, API Development, Heroku, Ruby on Rails Git Workflow, Full-Stack Development, MERN Stack, Node, D3, Material UI

### CONTACT

Rochester Hills, MI

mike.pakulak@gmail.com

586-604-5356

in /michaelpakulak

/LLuth0r

/mikepakulak.com

# **PROJECTS**

#### The Cellar

A wine bartering app built with Ruby on Rails and a React front-end.

#### Geosmin

Geosmin is a gourmet mushroom and microgreen urban farm store built with MERN stack.

#### **Make Cents**

Make Cent\$ is an Airtable and React financial planning app.

#### **Heroes & Villains**

Heroes & Villains provides a database full of your favorite superheroes and comic book villains.

## EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive General Assembly 2020 - 2021

B.S. Mechanical Engineering Kettering University

## INTERESTS

2001 - 2005

Hosted Plex Media Server Raspberry Pi / PC Builds 3D Printing / 3D Design

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Mechanical Engineer turned Software Developer. I have a passion for problem solving and design. I welcome new challenges and strive for innovation, excellence, and continuous growth. With more than 12 years of engineering experience, I have ample experience in the product development lifecycle and working with multidisciplinary teams to create amazing products. I'm a jack of all trades with a thirst for learning new skill-sets.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow

OCT 2020 - FEB 2021

Design and develop web based applications, integrating APIs, building back-end databases, functional and responsive user-interfaces utilizing MERN stack, Ruby on Rails, React, & Node all while following the GIT Workflow.

#### FCA, Design Release Engineer

MAY 2014 - MAR 2020

Led development and design including product criteria and specs for exterior components for the 2020 Truck of the Year, the Dodge RAM TRX and the Jeep Grand Cherokee SRT / Trackhawk. Coordinated with cross-functional teams to achieve program financial goals, timing, scope and quality objectives.

#### LTGL Group, Inc. dba Orangetheory Fitness, Owner/Operator

NOV 2016 - JAN 2019

Managed day-to-day business operations, including accounting, HR, marketing, and customer service. Developed sales goals for employees and tracked progress and milestones. Analyzed cost, materials, and vendors to achieve low cost alternatives for product and cost optimization.

#### General Motors, Design Release Engineer

NOV 2010 - MAY 2014

Led development and design including product criteria and specs for exterior components for the 2020 Truck of the Year, the Dodge RAM TRX and the Jeep Grand Cherokee SRT / Trackhawk. Coordinated with cross-functional teams to achieve program financial goals, timing, scope and quality objectives.

#### General Dynamics Land Systems, Systems Integration Engineeer

JAN 2006 - NOV 2010

Lead planning, integration, implementation, and technical direction of new engineering components. Developed BOMs, prototype part builds and logistics for installation on fielded vehicles across multiple U.S. Army bases.